# HARSH SHUKLA

| Chicago, IL - 60618 | Hshukla 2@ mail.depaul.edu | +1 773 456 7386 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/harsh-shukla-231b8b95/ |

### **SUMMARY**

Predictive Analytics graduate student with keen interest in Data analytics and Predictive modeling. Experienced in working with large and complex datasets in domains such as healthcare, police records, and customer behavior. Familiar with advance machine learning algorithms, data analytics, Regression, decision trees, ensemble learning and model validation. Able to explain analytical solutions using data visualization software to wide range of audience in a clear and precise manner. Proven team leader with broad, collaborative capabilities, detailed work and time bound.

**EDUCATION** 

**Master of Science in Predictive Analysis** 

2017 - 2019

DePaul University, Chicago, IL

**Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology** 

Gujarat Technological University (GTU), Gujarat, India

2012 - 2016

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL)
- Tableau
- Python, R, SPSS, SAS
- MS Office Suite (WORD, POWERPOINT, EXCEL)

### **PROJECTS**

### Probabilistic Classification of Lung Cancer in CT Scan Image

September 2018 – November 2018

LIDC (Lung Image Database Consortium collection) Data:

Implementation: Ongoing university Project where we implemented an ensembled Probabilistic classification model using R,

SAS and Tableau.

Visualizing Fatal Police Shooting in USA over Race, Poverty and Education Levels

**April 2018 – June 2018** 

Police killing in United States from 2015 to 2017 Data:

Implementation: Visualized racial gap between killings and whether poverty level and education level of the individual states affect

the killings by creating Diffusion Cartogram, choropleth, Bubble chart and heat map using R and Tableau.

## Predicting Probability of Customer's Likelihood to Frequent a Store Every Week

March 2018

Data: Departmental Store dataset without a target variable

Implementation: Generated Target variable using SQL from domain knowledge and then implemented logistic regression to predict

customer's likely hood to come back and purchase less than 3 products on weekly basis using SAS.

#### **Effective Factors on Mental health**

**January 2018 - March 2018** 

International survey of Mental Health in Tech workplace Data:

Implementation: Performed major data cleaning since it was survey data and built a logistic predictive regression model to check

the likely causes that affect mental health using SAS and SQL.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Information Services Department, DePaul University

Student Assistant at Classroom Technologies Division

September 2017 – Present

• Responsible for on the spot equipment trouble shooting, reconfiguring and installing projectors, equipment and software in classrooms. Providing Tech-support for classrooms. Communicating with clients and resolving queries. Working under time constraint. Mentoring new recruits.

# Web big2day

**August 2016 – July 2017** 

Content Writer and Client Collaboration

• Consulting directly with clients understanding their requirements and providing guidance or solution according to their need.

• Writing website content and understanding domain requirements of clients.

#### **Link Technologies**

August 2015 - May 2016

**Project Training** 

• Developing web portal for discounted student Regional Transportation Services with JSP in JAVA.

## Team Leader, Capstone Undergrad Project

August 2015 – May 2016

Active Volunteer at DISA (DePaul Indian Student Association)

**April 2019 - Present** 

Volunteer data science workshop host for Data Science students' group

January 2018 - Present